Guide to the Morris Tyler Family Collection Of John James Audubon
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Audubon Correspondence With Others, 1791-1982; Series II; 1.7; (4 boxes)
  - Coste, N. L. to JJA, 1840 Jul 29 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Croghan, John to VGA, 1841-44 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Cruikshank, F. to ?, [1835?] Dec 12 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Cumings, Samuel to VGA, 1843 Apr 22 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Cuthbertson, W. D.
    - To JJA, 1831 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - To LBA, 1834, 1835 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - To VGA, 1832-33, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Cuvier, Georges Baron to JJA, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - "D" general, 1828-41 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Davis, I. P. to JJA, 1836, 1837 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Delafield, Joseph
    - To JJA, 1840 Dec 5 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - To VGA, 1851 Feb 18 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Dunkin, Benjamin F.
    - To JJA, 1840 Jul 23 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - To VGA, 1842 Mar 3 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - "E" general, 1830-42 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Elliott, Ebenezer to JJA, 1836 Jan 19 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Empson, Charles W.
    - To [JJA?], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - To VGA, 1833 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Endicott, George to JJA, 1841 (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Everett, Edward
    - To JJA, 1830-32 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - To VGA, 1852 Dec 24 (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - "F" general, 1855, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - Finch-Hatton, George James to [JJA], 1836 (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Fish, Hamilton to VGA, 1851 Aug 19 (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Fisher, Miers to Jean Audubon, 1791-1802 (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - Fitzwilliam, Charles William Wentworth from JJA, 1844 Mar 27 (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Fothergill, E[lizabeth?]
    - To JJA, 1842 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - To LBA, 1831-37 (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - Fox, Charles James to [JJA?], n.d. (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Fox, George to JJA, 1836 Dec 9 (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - France. Ministère de l'Intérieur. Direction des Belles-Lettres, Sciences & Beaux-Arts to JJA, 1828 Oct (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - Fraser, W. to JJA, 1831 Apr 7 (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - "G" general, 1842-55, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - Gaston, William to JJA, 1833-35 (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - Gesson, G. to JJA, 1831 (Box 4, Folder 161)
  - Gibbs, Robert W. to JJA, 1836 Dec 27 (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - Goldmeister, Charles
    - To JWA, 1852 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - To VGA, 1857, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - Gould, John to ?, 1830 Jul 14 (Box 4, Folder 165)
  - Grimshaw, James to VGA, 1847-48 (Box 4, Folder 166)
    See also: Oversize, Box 15, folder 699
  - Grinnell, George Bird to [LBA?], 1874 Mar 9 (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - "Ha" general, 1830-46, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - "He - Hu" general, 1829-49 (Box 4, Folder 169)
  - Hall, Basil
    - To [JJA?], 1828, 1830 (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - From JJA, 1830 (Box 4, Folder 171)
  - Harlan, Richard
    - To JJA, 1830-39 (Box 4, Folder 172-174)
    - From JJA, 1830-39 (Box 4, Folder 175-178)
      See also: Oversize, Box 15, folder 700
    - To LBA, 1831-38 (Box 4, Folder 179)
    - To VGA, 1838, 1841 (Box 4, Folder 180)
  - Harris, Edward
    - To JJA, 1833-46 (Box 4, Folder 181-182)
    - To LBA, 1833, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 183)
    - To VGA, 1839-49 (Box 4, Folder 184)
  - Havell, Robert
    - To JJA, 1830-45 (Box 4, Folder 185)
    - To VGA, 1833 Aug 19 (Box 4, Folder 186)
  - Hay, W. Hammond to JJA (Box 4, Folder 187)
  - Heppenstall, Anne to LBA, 1838 Jan 3 (Box 4, Folder 188)
  - Heppenstall, John
    - To JJA, 1831-46 (Box 4, Folder 189-191)
    - To LBA, 1837 (Box 4, Folder 192)
    - To VGA, 1837, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 193)
  - Holbrook, John Edward to JJA, 1840, 1842 (Box 4, Folder 194)
  - Hooker, William Jackson
    - To JJA, 1833 Mar 4 (Box 4, Folder 195)
    - To VGA, 1839 Jun 6 (Box 4, Folder 196)
  - Hudson, Anne M. to JJA, 1829 (Box 4, Folder 197)
  - Huntington, D. to VGA, 1846, 1847 (Box 4, Folder 198)
  - "I" general, 1844, 1848 (Box 4, Folder 199)
  - Irving, Washington
    - To JJA, 1830[?] (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - From JJA, 1831 May 3 (Box 4, Folder 201)
  - "J" general, 1828-41 (Box 4, Folder 202)
  - Jay, John to JWA, 1849 Jan 24 (Box 4, Folder 203)
  - [Johnson?], Sarah to LBA, 1834 Feb 28 (Box 4, Folder 204)
  - "K" general, 1831-63 (Box 4, Folder 205)
  - Kemble, Adelaide to LBA, 1836, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 206)
  - Kidd, John Bartholomew
    - To JJA, 1828-36 (Box 5, Folder 207-210)
    - To LBA, 1832 Apr 1 (Box 5, Folder 211)
    - To VGA, 1833-34, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - King, John Crookshanks to VGA, 1854 Nov 24 (Box 5, Folder 213)
  - Kinnoul, Thomas Robert Hay-Drummond, Earl of to JJA, 1828 Feb 27 (Box 5, Folder 214)
  - "L" general, 1829-43 (Box 5, Folder 215)
  - Lamman, Charles to VGA, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - Lear, Edward to VGA, 1839 Aug 22 (Box 5, Folder 217)
  - LeConte, John to VGA and JWA, 1847-56 (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - Lefort, Jean
    - To VGA, 1855 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    - From VGA, 1855 Apr 3 (Box 5, Folder 220)
  - Lefroy, J. to JJA, 1842 (Box 5, Folder 221)
  - Lennox, James
    - To JJA, 1843, 1844 (Box 5, Folder 222)
    - To VGA, 1843-47 (Box 5, Folder 223)
  - Lester, C. Edwards from VGA, 1846 Mar 31 (Box 5, Folder 224)
  - Liddell, Sir Thomas Henry
    - To JJA, 1842 Nov 17 (Box 5, Folder 225)
    - From JJA, 1844 Mar 27 (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - Lincoln, Levi to VGA, 1852 Jul 27 (Box 5, Folder 227)
  - Lincoln, Thomas
    - To JJA, 1833 Jan 8 (Box 5, Folder 228)
    - From JWA, 1845 Mar 11 (Box 5, Folder 229)
  - Linnean Society to JJA, 1829, 1836 (Box 5, Folder 230)
  - Lizars, William H. to JJA, 1827-30 (Box 5, Folder 231)
  - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth to JJA, 1840 Sep 12 (Box 5, Folder 232)
  - Loreau, Henriette to [JWA or VGA], 1852-53 (Box 5, Folder 233)
  - Loudon, John Claudius
    - To [JJA?], 1828 (Box 5, Folder 234)
    - From VGA, 1833 (Box 5, Folder 235)
  - Louis Philippe, King of the French
    Letters are written on behalf of Louis Philippe by officials of his household
    - To JJA, 1828-34 (Box 5, Folder 236)
    - To [JWA or VGA], 1834 Jul 8 (Box 5, Folder 237)
  - "Mc" general, 1834-50 (Box 5, Folder 238)
  - "Mag - May" general, 1836-50 (Box 5, Folder 239)
  - "Me" general, 1832, 1842, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 240)
  - "Mi - Mu" general, 1831-53 (Box 5, Folder 241)
  - McCall, George A.
    - To JWA, 1853 Mar 17 (Box 5, Folder 242)
    - To VGA, 1851, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 243)
  - McCulloch, Thomas to JJA, 1834 Oct 28 (Box 5, Folder 244)
  - McCulloch, Thomas [Jr.?]
    - To JJA, 1842 Feb 14 (Box 5, Folder 245)
    - To JWA, 1843 Feb 24 (Box 5, Folder 246)
  - MacGillivary, William to JJA, 1831-38 (Box 5, Folder 247)
  - McMurtrie, Henry to JJA, 1830-31 (Box 5, Folder 248)
  - Mali, ----
    - To JJA, 1844 Jan 12 (Box 5, Folder 249)
    - From JJA, 1842 Nov 5 (Box 5, Folder 250)
  - Malloy, E. A. from JJA, n.d.
    See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 701
  - Martin, Maria to JJA, 1832 Jul 12 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - Moore, Joseph A. to JJA, 1842, 1846 (Box 5, Folder 252)
  - Morris, John Brande to JJA, 1836 Sep 19 (Box 5, Folder 253)
  - Morris, G.
    - To JWA, 1857 Mar 31 (Box 5, Folder 254)
    - To VGA, 1852 Aug 5 (Box 5, Folder 255)
  - Morton, Samuel George
    - To JJA, 1837-47 (Box 5, Folder 256)
    - To VGA, 1839-51 (Box 5, Folder 257)
  - Musson, George from LBA, 1834 Jul 29 (Box 5, Folder 258)
  - "N" general, 1831, 1846 (Box 5, Folder 259)
  - National Academy of Design to VGA, 1845-51 (Box 5, Folder 260)
  - Neill, Pat to JJA, 1831, 1834 (Box 5, Folder 261)
  - Nolte, V. to [JJA], 1836 Jul 23 (Box 5, Folder 262)
  - "O" general, 1837 (Box 5, Folder 263)
  - Oakes, William to JJA, 1833-34 (Box 5, Folder 264)
  - Ord, James Pickering to JJA, 1828 Dec 24 (Box 5, Folder 265)
  - Orr, Patrick
    - To JJA, 1836 (Box 5, Folder 266)
    - To VGA, 1833 Feb 19 (Box 5, Folder 267)
  - Owen, Richard to VGA, 1850 Jul 15 (Box 5, Folder 268)
  - "P" general, 1834-53 (Box 5, Folder 269)
  - Page, J. H. W.
    - To JJA, 1840, 1841 (Box 5, Folder 270)
    - To VGA, 1851 Feb 27 (Box 5, Folder 271)
  - Paine, Robert Treat to JJA, 1834-36 (Box 5, Folder 272)
  - Parkman, George and Eliza A. Parkman
    - To JJA, 1833-43, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 273-274)
      See also: Oversize, Box 15, folder 702
    - To LBA, 1833 (Box 5, Folder 275)
    - To VGA, 1835-48 (Box 5, Folder 276)
      See also: Oversize, Box 15, folder 703
  - Peabody, William Bourn Oliver to VGA, 1842, 1844 (Box 6, Folder 277)
  - Peale, Titian Ramsay to JJA, 1845 Dec 29 (Box 6, Folder 278)
  - Perkins, Thomas H. to JJA, 1832, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 279)
  - Pickering, Charles to VGA, 1847 (Box 6, Folder 280)
  - Pitois, M.
    - To JJA, 1837, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 281)
    - To [JWA or VGA], 1832, 1837 (Box 6, Folder 282)
  - Poinsett, Joel Robert
    - To JJA, 1840, 1841 (Box 6, Folder 283)
    - From JJA, 1840, 1841 (Box 6, Folder 284)
    - To VGA, 1850 (Box 6, Folder 285)
  - Ponsonby, ---- to JJA, 1836 Feb 15 (Box 6, Folder 286)
  - Poultney, Evan from JJA, 1834 Mar 26 (Box 6, Folder 287)
  - Putnam, George to VGA, 1844-51 (Box 6, Folder 288)
  - "R" general, 1828-52 (Box 6, Folder 289)
  - Raymond, ----
    - To JJA, 1848 Jan 4 (Box 6, Folder 290)
    - To VGA, 1849 Aug 21 (Box 6, Folder 291)
  - Rhett, Robert Barnwell to JJA, 1841 (Box 6, Folder 292)
  - Richardson, John to JJA, 1835, 1836 (Box 6, Folder 293)
  - Ridner, John P.
    - To JJA, 1840 Sep 25 (Box 6, Folder 294)
    - To VGA, 1844 Jul 3 (Box 6, Folder 295)
  - Robeson, Andrew to VGA, 1848 (Box 6, Folder 296)
  - Robison[?], John from JJA, 1831 May 9 (Box 6, Folder 297)
  - Roscoe, William to JJA, 1831 (Box 6, Folder 298)
    With: copy of letter of introduction to Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert du Motier, Marquis de Lafayette
  - Royal College of Surgeons to JJA, 1838-39 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - Rozier, Ferdinand to JJA, 1842 (Box 6, Folder 300)
  - Ryland, G. N. to JJA, 1841 Mar 28 (Box 6, Folder 301)
  - "S" general, 1831-54, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 302)
  - Salisbury, Edward E. to VGA, 1846-51 (Box 6, Folder 303)
  - Schmidt, Gustavus to JJA, 1832 Jul 20 (Box 6, Folder 304)
  - Scott, Winfield to JJA, 1845 Nov 21 (Box 6, Folder 305)
  - Scott-Moncrieff, Robert
    - To JJA, 1835 Oct 16 (Box 6, Folder 306)
    - From JJA, 1835 Oct 18 (Box 6, Folder 307)
  - Seabury, Joseph from JJA, 1840 Oct 22 (Box 6, Folder 308)
  - Selby, Prideaux John to JJA, 1828-29 (Box 6, Folder 309)
  - Sergeant, E. N.[?] to JJA, 1828, 1829 (Box 6, Folder 310)
  - Seward, William H. [Henry?] to JJA, 1844 Aug 4 (Box 6, Folder 311)
  - Shattuck, George C. to JJA, 1833-47 (Box 6, Folder 312)
  - Shattuck, George C., Jr.
    - To JJA, 1836-46 (Box 6, Folder 313)
    - To JWA [and VGA?], 1835, 1836 (Box 6, Folder 314)
  - Simpson, George, Sir to JJA, 1846 Jan 24 (Box 6, Folder 315)
  - Smith, Gideon B. to VGA, 1851 Feb 22 (Box 6, Folder 316)
  - Smith, William S. to JJA, 1841 Dec 26 (Box 6, Folder 317)
  - South Carolina. Legislature from JJA, 1840 Jul 6 (Box 6, Folder 318)
  - Spencer, William George from JJA, 1844 Mar 27 (Box 6, Folder 319)
  - Sprague, Lorenzo to VGA, 1855 (Box 6, Folder 320)
  - Stewart, William Drummond
    - To JJA [fragment], n.d. (Box 6, Folder 321)
    - From JJA, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 322)
  - [Stickney, Gilbert?] from JJA, 1831 (Box 6, Folder 323)
  - Storer, D. Humphreys to JJA, 1841, 1843 (Box 6, Folder 324)
  - Sully, Jane to LBA, 1827 Feb 11 (Box 6, Folder 325)
    Includes transcript in Sully's hand of JJA letter of [1826] Dec 28 to Thomas Sully
  - Sully, Thomas to JJA, 1829, 1832 (Box 6, Folder 326)
  - Summer, A. G. to [VGA?], 1847, 1848 (Box 6, Folder 327)
  - Swainson, Mary to JJA, 1828 Dec 22 (Box 6, Folder 328)
  - Swainson, William to JJA, 1828-35, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 329-330)
  - Swartout, Samuel to JJA, 1836 Oct 14 (Box 6, Folder 331)
  - Swinbourne, Sir John to JJA, 1828 May 2 (Box 6, Folder 332)
  - "T" general, 1845-65 (Box 6, Folder 333)
  - Thorne, Herman to VGA, 1836 Dec 5 (Box 6, Folder 334)
  - Townsend, John Kirk to VGA, 1839-48 (Box 6, Folder 335)
  - Traill, Thomas Stewart to JJA, 1828 Aug 19 (Box 6, Folder 336)
  - Trudeau, J. to JJA, 1857 May 27 (Box 6, Folder 337)
  - United States. Treasury Department
    - To JJA, 1833 Dec 16 (Box 6, Folder 338)
    - To VGA, 1851-57 (Box 6, Folder 339)
  - "V" general, 1840, 1841 (Box 6, Folder 340)
  - Van Rensselaer, Stephen to JJA, 1837 (Box 6, Folder 341)
  - Victoria, Queen of Great Britain from JJA (Box 6, Folder 342)
  - Vigors, Nicholas Aylward to JJA, 1829-30 (Box 6, Folder 343)
  - "W" general, 1831-50 (Box 6, Folder 344)
  - Wadsworth, James to VGA, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 345)
  - Walker, Thomas to [JJA], 1831 Feb 27 (Box 6, Folder 346)
  - Ward, James W. to ?, 1852 May 2 (Box 6, Folder 347)
  - Warren, John Collins to [VGA or JWA], 1852 Aug 17 (Box 6, Folder 348)
  - Washington Art Association to JWA, 1856 (Box 6, Folder 349)
  - Webster, Daniel to [JJA?], 1841 Jul 3 (Box 6, Folder 350)
  - Wilkes, Charles
    - To JJA, 1846 Mar 18 (Box 6, Folder 351)
    - From JJA, 1846 Mar 15 (Box 6, Folder 352)
  - William D. Ticknor Co. to VGA, 1852 Jun 11 (Box 6, Folder 353)
  - Wilson, James
    - To JJA, 1830-45, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 354)
    - To VGA, 1844 Nov 20 (Box 6, Folder 355)
  - Wilson, John from JJA, 1831 Jul 1 (Box 6, Folder 355a)
  - Witham, Eliza to LBA, 1831 Jun 22 (Box 6, Folder 356)
  - Wright, A. B. to JJA, 1841 Aug 21 (Box 6, Folder 357)
  - Yale, Leroy N. to JJA, 1842 Aug 24 (Box 6, Folder 358)
  - Yarrell, William to JJA, 1835, 1840 (Box 6, Folder 359)
  - Zoological Society [Great Britain]
    - To JJA, 1828-47 (Box 6, Folder 360)
    - To LBA, 1836 Aug 5 (Box 6, Folder 361)
    - To VGA, 1836 Jan 30 (Box 6, Folder 362)
  - Unidentified to JJA, 1832-42 (Box 6, Folder 363)
    See also: Box 7, folder 434
  - Unidentified from JJA, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 364)
  - Unidentified from [JWA?], 1836 Apr 10 (Box 6, Folder 365)
  - Unidentified to VGA, 1836, 1840, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 366)
  - Later correspondence, 1870-1892 (Box 6, Folder 367)
    Incl: letter from J. Pierpont Morgan
  - Later correspondence, 1953-1975 (Box 6, Folder 368)
    Incl: letters from Prescott Bush
- Audubon-Related Correspondence, 1795-1855; Series III; 0.4; (1 box)
  Series III, Audubon-Related Correspondence is organized in two subseries, Letters of Introduction and Other Audubon-Related Correspondence. Both subseries are arranged alphabetically by correspondent and names of letter recipients are given when known. Additional Audubon-Related Correspondence can be found in the Scrapbook subseries of Series VII, Autograph Collection.
  - LETTERS OF INTRODUCTION
    - Ashburton, Alexander Baring Baron, 1842 Jul 24 (Box 7, Folder 369)
    - Bail[?], John M. to John A. Collier, 1844 Jul 29 (Box 7, Folder 370)
    - Blainville, [Henri Marie Ducrotay?] de to ---- Drapier, 1833 Jul 7 (Box 7, Folder 371)
    - Blainville, [Henri Marie Ducrotay?] de to ---- Otto, 1833 Jul 7
    - Blainville, [Henri Marie Ducrotay?] de to ---- Soemmering[?], 1833 Jul 7
    - Blainville, [Henri Marie Ducrotay?] de to ---- Lichstenstein, 1833 Jul 7
    - Bonaparte, Charles Lucien to C. J.[?] Temminck, 1825 Dec 5 (Box 7, Folder 372)
    - Brand, W. T. to James Sterrett for VGA, 1840 Oct 23
    - Brewer, T. M. to T. C. Crittenden (Box 7, Folder 373)
    - Brewer, T. M. to Seth ----, n.d.
    - Chouteau, Pierre to Peter A. Sarpy, 1843 Apr 17 (Box 7, Folder 374)
    - Cooper, Thomas to Col. Gamble, 1833 Oct 21
    - Clinton, Dewitt to Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert du Motier, Marquis de Lafayette, 1826 Oct 27 (Box 7, Folder 375)
    - Everett, A. H. to Charles Everett, 1833 Feb 26 (Box 7, Folder 376)
    - Galindo, Juan to don Lorenzo Tabula, 1836 Jun 11 (Box 7, Folder 377)
    - Hall, Basil to Miss White, 1827 Jan 10 (Box 7, Folder 378)
    - Hall, Basil to ---- Buckland, 1827 Feb 26
    - Hall, Basil, 1827 April 1
    - Hall, J. Prescott to R. M. Blatchford, 1843 Dec 13 (Box 7, Folder 379)
    - Harmon[?], Peter to the Conde de la Reunion, 1840 Oct 19
    - Harris, Edward to J. J. Spencer, 1833 Apr 13
    - Hay, W[illiam Hammond] to Edward Vernon, 1827 Mar 18 (Box 7, Folder 380)
    - Hay, W[illiam Hammond] to ---- Ewbank, 1827 Mar 18
    - Hay, W[illiam Hammond] to Lord Stanley, 1831 Aug 2
    - Hook, ---- to ---- Morgan, 1836 Nov 12 (Box 7, Folder 381)
    - Irving, Washington to Martin Van Buren, 1830 Oct 18 (Box 7, Folder 382)
    - Irving, Washington to William C. Rives, 1830 Oct 18
    - Jackson, Andrew to Samuel Overton, 1824 Nov 1 (Box 7, Folder 383)
    - Jackson, Andrew, 1830 Mar 20
    - Jameson, Robert to Sir Charles ----, 1827 Apr (Box 7, Folder 384)
    - Jesup, Thomas to Duncan Lamont Clinch, 1831 Oct 3 (Box 7, Folder 385)
    - Jesup, Thomas to John L. Engle, 1831 Oct 3
    - Jesup, Thomas to John Paige, 1831 Oct 3
    - Johnson, David to J. Nicholson, 1835 Dec 18 (Box 7, Folder 386)
    - Jussieu, [Antoine Laurent?] de to Alexander von Humboldt, 1833
    - King, Charles to ---- Field, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 387)
    - King, ---- to N. M. Rothschild, 1834 Apr 14
    - King, ---- to ---- Brothers Co, 1834 Aug 6
    - Le Conte, John to William Gaston, 1831 Sep 16 (Box 7, Folder 388)
    - Lesueur, A. to Eyriés frere & Comp., 1824 Feb 12
    - Macomb, A. E. to Colonel Thayer for JWA Menlove, Edward to S. C. Tennant for VGA (Box 7, Folder 389)
    - Morris, John B. to Robert Taylor, 1833 Oct 11 (Box 7, Folder 390)
    - Paravey, C. A. to P. Paravey, 1836 Oct 5 (Box 7, Folder 391)
    - Parker, Samuel to Joseph Parker, 1830 Jun 10
    - Peale, Titian Ramsay to J. H. Callan, 1847 Feb 22 (Box 7, Folder 392)
    - Rickman, Thomas to J. S. Harford, 1830 Jun 1 (Box 7, Folder 393)
    - Rickman, Thomas to Charles Bowles Fripp, 1830 Jun 1
    - Roscoe, E. to E. Roberts, 1826 Aug 15 (Box 7, Folder 394)
    - Ryland, G. N., 1842 Sep 21 (Box 7, Folder 395)
    - Sismondi, Jean-Charles-Léonard Simonde de
    - Société entomologique de France to ---- Kollar, 1833 Jul 8 (Box 7, Folder 396)
    - Société entomologique de France to ---- Klug, 1833 Jul 8
      Written by the secretary of the Société, A. Lefebvre
    - Swartwout, Samuel to W. J. Duane[?], 1833 Sep 23 (Box 7, Folder 397)
    - Taney, R. B. [Roger Brooke?] to McClintock Young, 1836 Nov 5 (Box 7, Folder 398)
    - Trevelyan, W. C. [Walter Calverley?] to I.[?] Milford, 1827 Jun 2 (Box 7, Folder 399)
    - Turner, W. to J.G. Robberds, 1827 Apr 18
    - United States. Consulate (Paris, France) for JWA and VGA, 1836 Mar 24 (Box 7, Folder 400)
    - United States. Department of State, 1832 Jul 17 (Box 7, Folder 401)
    - United States. Office of the Superintendent of Indian Affairs to D. Miller, 1843 Apr 19 (Box 7, Folder 402)
    - United States. War Department, 1842 Jul 25 (Box 7, Folder 403)
    - Vigors, Nicholas Aylward to William [Morgan?] Kinsey, 1828 Mar 1 (Box 7, Folder 404)
    - Vigors, Nicholas Aylward, 1828 Mar 1
    - Webb, James Watson to James Hamilton, 1836 Oct 11 (Box 7, Folder 405)
    - Webster, Daniel, 1842 Jul 24
      See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 704
    - White, Joseph M. to James G. Ringgold, 1831 Sep 14 (Box 7, Folder 406)
    - Unidentified, 1828 Aug 26 (Box 7, Folder 407)
  - OTHER AUDUBON-RELATED CORRESPONDENCE
    - Abert, John James to Richard Harlan, 1831 (Box 7, Folder 408)
    - Adams, John Quincy to George Parkman, 1835 Mar 28 (Box 7, Folder 409)
    - Bonaparte, Charles Lucien to ---- Lefort, 1855 (Box 7, Folder 410)
    - Brainerd, John to John Bachman, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 411)
    - Eden, George to Lord Stanley, 1830 Jun 20 (Box 7, Folder 412)
    - Formon, Lewis to David Ross, 1795 May 8 (Box 7, Folder 413)
    - Gibbs, Lewis to John Bachman, 1835 Sep 7 (Box 7, Folder 414)
    - Gray, John Edward to ---- Phillips, 1852 Jun 7 (Box 7, Folder 415)
    - Harlan, Richard to John Bachman, 1834 Feb 23 (Box 7, Folder 416)
    - Harlan, Richard to Nicholas Berthoud, 1836 Oct 5
    - Harris, Thaddeus William to G. C. Shattuck, 1837 May 13 (Box 7, Folder 417)
    - Henslow, J. S. to Robert Havell, 1832 Jun 1 (Box 7, Folder 418)
    - Hill, Alexander to Robert Havell, 1829 Sep 4
    - King, James G. to Nicholas Berthoud, 1836 Jul 12 (Box 7, Folder 419)
    - Kidd, Joseph Bartholomew to Robert Havell, 1829, 1834 (Box 7, Folder 420)
    - Lincoln, Levi to George Parkman, 1833 Jan 25 (Box 7, Folder 421)
    - Louis-Philippe, King of the French to Robert Havell, 1829 Jun 25 (Box 7, Folder 422)
      Written on behalf of Louis-Philippe by his secretary
    - McCall, George A. to John Bachman, 1837 Jul (Box 7, Folder 423)
    - Neal, John to George C. Parkman, 1833, 1834 (Box 7, Folder 424)
    - Neal, John to George C. Shattuck, 1836 Sep 23
    - Osborne, George William Frederick to William Martyn, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 425)
    - Percy, Edmund to ---- Hall, 1844 Apr 3 (Box 7, Folder 426)
    - Ross, David to Thomas Ladd, 1805 Feb (Box 7, Folder 427)
    - Seaton, William Winston to ---- Lanman, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 428)
    - Stuart, Dudley Lord to Robert Havell, 1830 Mar 27 (Box 7, Folder 429)
    - Trumbull, John to Josiah Quincy, 1829 May 10 (Box 7, Folder 430)
    - United States. Department of War to J. R. Poinsett, 1840 Oct 6 (Box 7, Folder 431)
    - United States. Navy Department to J. J. Abert, 1831 Dec 21 (Box 7, Folder 432)
    - Waller, Nathan to ?, 1830 (Box 7, Folder 433)
    - Unidentified to Robert Havell, 1831 Dec 16 (Box 7, Folder 434)
    - Unidentified, n.d.
      See also: Box 6, folder 363
- Writings, 1826-74; Series IV; 0.8; (2 boxes)
  Series IV, Writings is organized in two subseries, Writings of John James Audubon and Writings of Others, and is arranged alphabetically by author and then by title.
  - WRITINGS OF JOHN JAMES AUDUBON
    - "An Account of the habits of the American Goshawk...," printed version, The Edinburgh Journal of Natural and Geographical Science, 1831 Mar (Box 8, Folder 435)
    - Birds of America
      - Exhibition announcement, printed, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 436)
      - House of Representatives Executive Document No. 68, printed, five copies, 1856 (Box 8, Folder 437)
      - Prospectus, holograph, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 705
      - Prospectus, printed, three copies, 1831 (Box 8, Folder 438)
        With: note, in John James Audubon's hand
      - Sketches of bird anatomy, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 439)
      - Subscription announcement, printed, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 440)
      - Subscription list, holograph, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 441)
      - Subscription list, printed, with annotations, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 442)
      - Vol. 6, p. 10-40, printed, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 443)
    - "Descriptions of New Species of Quadrupeds Inhabiting North America," printed, 1841 Oct 5 (Box 8, Folder 444)
    - Journal, transcript, fragment, manuscript, 1826 Jun (Box 8, Folder 445)
    - Journal No. 5, transcript, manuscript, 1843 Aug 5-13 (Box 8, Folder 446)
    - "The Lobster the Constable and the Mayor," holograph (Box 8, Folder 447)
    - "My Seal" [photocopy], n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 706
    - Ornithological Biography
      Related Materials
      See also: "The White Perch and its favorite Bait"
      - Introduction to volume 3, drafts; and unidentified drafts, holograph
        See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 707
      - "Brown Creeper" and "California Nuthatch," holograph (Box 8, Folder 448)
      - "Canvas back Duck," holograph, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 708
      - Copyright, partly printed, 1836 Aug 5-13 (Box 8, Folder 449)
      - Fragments, holograph, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 450)
      - "Great Northern Diver," holograph
        See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 709
      - "Hairy Woodpecker," holograph, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 710
      - "The Mallard," holograph, n.d.
        See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 711
      - Reviews, printed, 1835, 1840 (Box 8, Folder 451-452)
    - A Story of Meadville, Boston: Eastburn's Press, printed monograph, 1846 (Box 8, Folder 453)
    - Viviparous Quadrupeds of North America